

ASMITHA R E

Data Engineer

E: asmithal999@gmail.com

P: 7598443567

SKILLS

SQL

IICS

Snowflake

HOBBIES

I enjoy Writing

LANGUAGES

Tamil

English

PROFILE

Passionate Data Engineer with 2+ years of experience with good hands on experience with Informatica Cloud (IICS) and Snowflake data warehousing tool. Have migrated data from SAP source system to Snowflake using the ETL tools and have scheduled the jobs using UC4 scheduler. Have done transformations in IICS as well as Snowflake. Able to work in agile environment. Wishing to learn new technologies and adapt to the environment.

EDUCATION

BE | Thiagarajar College of Engineering, Madurai

Jul 2016 - May 2020

Graduated Bachelor of Engineering in the stream of Computer Science of Engineering with 93%

EXPERIENCE

Data Engineer | LTI, Chennai

Sep 2021 - Present

Generation of transformed data for the customer and retail services related reports by applying transformation logic on the source raw data which is being leveraged in the snowflake. Views are created on top of the raw data using SQL queries and that is being used by the reporting side. Automation of the process is also in progress.

Graduate Engineer Trainee | LTI, WFH

Aug 2020 - Sep 2021

Have attended training on SQL and worked in automating the data loading process from SAP system to Snowflake using IICS – cloud by creating mappings, mapping tasks and task flows in IICS and the respective tables creation in Snowflake using SQL. Regular monitoring of data loading is done to assure proper automation of data loading is done.

COURSES

MBA (Part Time) | Anna University

Dec 2021

LINKEDIN

www.linkedin.com/in/ asmitha-r-e-768523168